A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 3255-6261 FA739B
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Santiago office budget for FY 1973 (Reports 005855), 1972 (Box 262)
  Social planning -- Chile; Social sciences -- Chile; Agricultural assistance -- Chile; Population assistance -- Chile; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Finance; Endowments -- Chile -- Evaluation; Ford Foundation. Field Office Santiago; Ford Foundation. Latin America and the Caribbean; Ford Foundation
- Budget proposal for fiscal year 1973-Brazil (Reports 005856), 1972 (Box 262)
  Memo to William Carmichael dated February 7, 1972.
  Brazil budget proposal for FY 1973 ...
  Agricultural assistance -- Brazil; Population assistance -- Brazil; Educational assistance -- Brazil; Endowments -- Brazil -- Evaluation; Ford Foundation. Latin America and the Caribbean; Ford Foundation
- FY1973 allocation and program emphasis, office for Latin America and the Caribbean (Reports 005857), 1978 (Box 262)
  Memo to David Bell dated January 31, 1972.
  Office for Latin America and Caribbean FY 1973 ...
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Finance; Endowments -- Latin America -- Evaluation; Endowments -- Caribbean Area -- Evaluation; Ford Foundation. Latin America and the Caribbean; Ford Foundation
- Lima (Peru) field office FY 1973 budget: narrative statement January 1972. (Reports 005858) (Box 262)
  Social planning -- Peru; Educational assistance -- Peru; Agricultural assistance -- Peru; Population assistance -- Peru; Social sciences -- Research -- Peru; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Finance; Endowments -- Peru -- Evaluation; Ford Foundation. Latin America and the Caribbean; Ford Foundation
- Planning, exploration, and evaluation agenda (Reports 005859), 1972 (Box 262)
  Memo to David Bell dated January 27, 1972.
  International finance; International cooperation; Ford Foundation. International Division; Ford Foundation. Latin America and the Caribbean
- A modified schedule for program planning budgeting (Reports 005860), 1972 (Box 262)
  Staff memo dated January 14, 1972.
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Management; Charity organization; Ford Foundation. Office of the President; Ford Foundation
- FY 1973 - program management budget (Reports 005861), 1972 (Box 262)
  Memo to William Carmichael dated July 28, 1972.
  2 p. + attachments: tables
  Program management budget, FY 1973 ...
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Management; Ford Foundation. Field Office Mexico City; Ford Foundation. Latin America and the Caribbean
- Fiscal year 1973 program budget for the Mexico city Field Office (Reports 005862), 1972 (Box 262)
  Population assistance -- Latin America; Agriculture and state -- Latin America; Educational assistance -- Latin America; Social sciences -- Latin America; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Finance; Endowments -- Latin America -- Evaluation; Ford Foundation. Field Office Mexico City; Ford Foundation
- FY 1973 program management budget for Latin America and the Caribbean (Reports 005863), 1972 (Box 263)
  Memo to Arthur Trottenberg dated August 11, 1972.
  1 p. + attachments: principally tables
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Finance; Endowments -- Latin America; Ford Foundation. Latin America and the Caribbean; Ford Foundation
- Buenos Aires program budget FY 1973 (Reports 005864), 1972 (Box 263)
  Memo to William Carmichael dated February 5, 1972.
  various pagings: table
  Agriculture -- Research -- Latin America; Agriculture and state -- Latin America; Social sciences -- Latin America; Sociology, Rural -- Study and teaching (Graduate) -- Latin America; Educational assistance -- Latin America; Population assistance -- X,; Ford Foundation. Field Office Buenos Aires; Ford Foundation
- Ford Foundation Office for Colombia and Venezuela: proposed FY 1973 budget (Reports 005865), 1972 (Box 263)
  Agriculture -- Research -- Latin America; Educational assistance -- Latin America; Population assistance -- Latin America; Urbanization -- Latin America; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Finance; Charity organization -- Latin America; Ford Foundation. Latin America and the Caribbean; Ford Foundation
- Emerging roles of agricultural economists working in international research institutions such as IRRI and CIMMYT (Reports 005866), 1973 (Box 263)
  Agricultural economists working in international research ...
  Agriculture -- Research -- Developing countries; Agriculture -- Economic aspects -- Developing countries; Agriculture -- Social aspects -- Developing countries; Agricultural economists -- Developing countries; Agricultural assistance -- Developing countries; International Rice Research Institute; International Maize and Wheat Improvement Center
- Foundation work on agriculture, resources, and rural development (Reports 005867), 1979 (Box 263)
  Memo to Franklin Thomas dated August 15, 1979.
  Nutrition -- Research -- Developing countries; Food supply -- Developing Countries; Agriculture -- Research -- Developing countries; Agricultural resources -- Developing countries; Agricultural assistance -- Developing countries; Rural development -- Developing countries; Ford Foundation. International Division
- Special paper: notes on program strategies which seek to advance the advance the welfare of the rural poor (Reports 005868), 1979 (Box 263)
  Presented at International Division conference, March 21-24, 1979. Related to: Session 1a, March 21, 1979. -- T.p.
  PAPER Conference (Mar. 21-24, 1979: New York, N.Y.)
  Agriculture -- Economic aspects -- Developing countries; Rural poor -- Research -- Developing countries; Rural poor -- Services for -- Developing countries; Food supply -- Developing Countries; Nutrition policy -- Developing countries; Ford Foundation. International Division
- Agriculture, natural resources and related rural development in developing countries (Reports 005869), 1980 (Box 263)
  Agriculture -- Developing Countries; Natural resources -- Developing countries; Rural development -- Developing countries; Food supply -- Developing Countries; Ford Foundation. International Division
- Report on a Ford Foundation rural economy team's visit to China (Reports 005870), 1980 (Box 263)
  Ford members include: Lowell S. Hardin, ReedHertford, Dwight H. Perkins, and Sumter L. Travers.
  Ford Foundation rural economy ...
  Rural development -- China -- Sociological aspects; Agriculture -- Social aspects -- China; Agriculture -- Research -- China; Social sciences -- Research -- China; Women in development -- China; Women in agriculture -- China; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific
- Notes on agricultural, rural, resources projects and program, Cairo office (Reports 005871), 1981 (Box 263)
  Agricultural, rural, resources projects and program: Cairo office
  Agriculture -- Research -- Africa, North; Agriculture -- Research -- Middle East; Agricultural development projects -- Africa, North; Agricultural development projects -- Middle East; Agricultural assistance -- Africa, North; Agricultural assistance; Ford Foundation. Field Office Cairo; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa
- Current status of agriculturally related grants in West Africa, February 1981 (Reports 005872) (Box 263)
  File memo dated March 2, 1981.
  Agriculturally related grants in West Africa, February 1981...
  Agriculture -- Research -- Africa, West; Agricultural assistance -- Africa, West; Women in agriculture -- Africa, West; Food policy -- Africa, West; Endowments -- Africa, West -- Evaluation; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa
- Notes on Middle East Agricultural - Resources Program (Reports 005873), 1980 (Box 263)
  Memo to William Carmichael dated February 1, 1980.
  Middle East Agricultural/Resources Program
  Agriculture -- Research -- Middle East; Agriculture -- Research -- Africa, North; Agricultural resources -- Middle East; Agricultural resources -- Africa, North; Agricultural assistance -- Middle East; Agricultural assistance -- Africa, North; Endowments; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa
- Notes on PRC contacts and discussions: Seventeenth International Conference of Agricultural Economists, Banff, Alberta, Canada, September 3-11 (Reports 005874), 1979 (Box 263)
  Memo to John Bresnan datedSeptember 12, 1979.
  Seventeenth International Conference of Agricultural Economists, Banf, Alberta, Canada, Sept. 3-11, 1979
  Agricultural economists -- Congresses; Agriculture -- Economic aspects -- Congresses; Agriculture -- Economic aspects -- China; Agriculture -- Social aspects -- China; International Association of Agricultural Economists
- Notes on my West African program visit, April 17 - May 2 (Reports 005875), 1979 (Box 263)
  Memo to Messrs. Carmichael, Drysdale, and Kiene, dated May 16, 1979.
  West African program visit, April 17 - May 2, 1979 ...
  Educational assistance -- Africa, West; Education, Higher -- Africa, West; Universities and colleges -- Africa, West; Agriculture -- Research -- Africa, West; Rural development -- Africa, West; Endowments -- Africa, West -- Evaluation; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa
- Attached notes on my Eastern and Southern Africa visits - January 26 - February 13 (Reports 005876), 1979 (Box 263)
  File memo dated February 20, 1979.
  Eastern and Southern Africa visits - January 26 - February 13, 1979
  Agriculture -- Research -- Africa, East; Agriculture -- Research -- Africa, Southern; Agriculture -- Study and teaching -- Africa, East; Agriculture -- Study and teaching -- Africa, Southern; Endowments -- Africa, East -- Evaluation; Endowments -- Africa, Southern; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa
- Summary of our observations and program suggestions, Middle East and North Africa (Reports 005877), 1978 (Box 263)
  Memo to William Carmichael dated March 1, 1978.
  Middle East and North Africa: summary of our observations and program suggestions
  Agriculture -- Research -- Africa, North; Agriculture -- Research -- Middle East; Agricultural assistance -- Africa, North; Agricultural assistance -- Middle East; Endowments -- Africa, North -- Evaluation; Endowments -- Middle East -- Evaluation; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa
- Observations on our program visits in Latin America, January 8-28 (Reports 005878), 1978 (Box 263)
  Memo to James Himes dated February 14, 1978.
  Program visits in Latin America, January 8-28, 1978
  Agriculture -- Research -- Latin America; Agricultural assistance -- Latin America; Endowments -- Latin America -- Evaluation; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa
- Agricultural programming in the Middle East region (Reports 005879), 1977 (Box 263)
  File memo dated February 15, 1977.
  Agriculture -- Research -- Middle East; Agriculture -- Economic aspects -- Middle East; Agricultural productivity -- Middle East; Agricultural economists -- Middle East; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa
- Notes on Middle East-Africa trip, January 15-February 27, 1976 (Reports 005880) (Box 263)
  Memo to Robert Edwards and David Bell, dated March 1, 1976.
  Middle East-Africa trip, January 15-February 27, 1976
  Agriculture -- Research -- Middle East; Agriculture -- Economic aspects -- Middle East; Agriculture -- Social aspects -- Middle East; Agriculture and state -- Middle East; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa
- Discussion notes on North Africa Agriculture Program (Reports 005881), 1976 (Box 263)
  Memo to L. S. Hartin, Wilbert LeMelle and John Nellis, dated January 26, 1976.
  North Africa Agriculture Program
  Agriculture -- Africa, North; Agricultural assistance -- Africa, North; Rural development -- Africa, North; Social sciences -- Africa, North; Endowments -- Africa, North -- Evaluation; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa
- Nine points to ponder relative to future rice production in West Pakistan (Reports 005882), 1969 (Box 263)
  Memo to Robert Havener dated October 23, 1969.
  Rice production in West Pakistan ...
  Rice -- Research -- Pakistan; Crop yields -- Pakistan; Agricultural productivity -- Pakistan; Agriculture -- Research -- Pakistan; Agriculture -- Economic aspects -- Pakistan; Agriculture and state -- Pakistan; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific
- Working paper on rice improvement for the Annual Developmental Meeting, Department of Agriculture, West Pakistan (Reports 005883), 1966 (Box 263)
  Research on rice in West Pakistan.
  06600433
  Department of Agriculture, West Pakistan: annual development meeting, March, 1966
  Rice -- Research -- Pakistan -- West Pakistan; International Rice Research Institute
- Recommendations for the next steps in rice improvement in West Pakistan (Reports 005884), 1968 (Box 263)
  Letter to Hon. Malik Khuda Bakhesh Buch, Minister of Agriculture, West Pakistan, dated March 25, 1968.
  Rice improvement in West Pakistan: recommendations
  Rice -- Research -- Pakistan; Crop yields -- Pakistan; Agricultural productivity -- Pakistan; Agriculture -- Study and teaching -- Pakistan; Agriculture -- Research -- Pakistan; Agriculture and state -- Pakistan
- West Pakistan's accelerated rice improvement program in cooperation with the International Rice Research Institute (Reports 005885), 1966 (Box 263)
  ... based on a tour of West Pakistan rice research stations in October 1966. --T.p.
  54 p.: tables
  Rice -- Research -- Pakistan; Crop yields -- Pakistan; Agricultural productivity -- Pakistan; Agriculture -- Economic aspects -- Pakistan; Agriculture and state -- Pakistan
- Observations on the emerging rice marketing problems in East Pakistan (Reports 005886), 1971 (Box 263)
  31 p. + apendix
  Rice marketing in East Pakistan
  Rice -- Bangladesh; Crop yields -- Bangladesh; Agriculture -- Economic aspects -- Bangladesh; Agricultural productivity -- Bangladesh; Agriculture and state -- Bangladesh; Ford Foundation
- Rice stem borer control (Reports 005887), 1970 (Box 263)
  24 p. + appendix: chart
  West Pakistan Rice Improvement Reports, No. RW23
  Rice -- Diseases and pests -- Pakistan; Borers (Insects) -- Control -- Pakistan; Insecticides -- Research -- Pakistan; Agriculture -- Research -- Pakistan
- Potential rice production and the needs for inputs (Reports 005889), 1966 (Box 263)
  Letter to Amir Ahmad Khan, Secretary of Agriculture, Government of West Pakistan, dated November 17, 1966.
  Rice -- Research -- Pakistan; Agriculture and state -- Pakistan
- Projections of yields, production and the required main inputs by introduction of the new high-yielding dwarf varieties of coarse rice (Reports 005890), 1966 (Box 263)
  Memo to Amir Ahmad Khan, Secretary of Agriculture, Government of West Pakistan, dated November 14, 1966.
  Rice -- Research -- Pakistan; Crop yields -- Pakistan; Agricultural productivity -- Pakistan; Agriculture and state -- Pakistan
- Comments on the Accelerated Maize, Bajra and Jowar Program for West Pakistan (Reports 005891), 1967 (Box 263)
  Memo to Hon. Malik Khuda Bakhsh Butcha and Amir Ahmed Kah, Government of West Pakistan, dated August 1, 1967.
  Accelerated, Maize, Bajra and Jowar Program for West Pakistan
  Corn -- Research -- Pakistan; Grain -- Research -- Pakistan; Crop yields -- Pakistan; Agricultural productivity -- Pakistan
- Discussion paper: Planning for the Foundation's program in 1973 and beyond (Reports 005892), 1972 (Box 263)
  See also: James A. Gardner's comment on Discussion Paper: "Subjects of Emerging Promise or Significance."
  34 p.: table
  Planning for the Foundation's program in 1973 and beyond
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Finance; Endowments -- United States -- Evaluation; Ford Foundation. Office of the President; Ford Foundation; Ford Foundation Management
- Report on visit to East Africa (Reports 005893), 1967 (Box 263)
  Visit to East Africa
  Education, Higher -- Africa, East; Universities and colleges -- Africa, East; Educational assistance -- Africa, East; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa
- Observations on our Asian trip September - October 13 (Reports 005894), 1978 (Box 263)
  Memo to N. Collins and F. Korten, Dated October 30, 1978.
  Asian trip, September 14 - October 13, 1978 ...
  Agriculture -- Research -- Southeast Asia; Agriculture -- Research -- Middle East; Agricultural productivity -- Southeast Asia; Agricultural productivity -- Middle East; Crop yields -- Southeast Asia; Crop yields -- Middle East; Agricultural assistance; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific
- Notes on Niger (Reports 005895), 1974 (Box 263)
  International Division/Middle East and Africa/Board of Trustees
  Economic development -- Niger; Agriculture -- Study and teaching -- Niger; Education -- Niger; Economic assistance -- Niger; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa
- The program to serve public education (Reports 005896), 1971 (Box 263)
  L72-38
  Education -- Research -- United States; Public schools -- United States; Educational equalization -- United States; Ford Foundation. Public Education Program
- Education and research program review: A first response public education (Reports 005897), 1972 (Box 263)
  18 p.: tables
- An analysis of current enrollment trends at the 51 private, senior, traditionally black institutions of higher learning (Reports 005898), 1971 (Box 263)
  10 p.: tables
  Black institutions of higher learning
  African American universities and colleges -- Research; African American college students; African Americans -- Education, Higher; Universities and colleges -- United States; College attendance -- United States -- Statistics; Education, Higher -- United States
- Ethnic colleges (Reports 005899), 1971 (Box 263)
  Minorities -- Education, Higher -- United States; Universities and colleges -- United States; Public universities and colleges -- United States; College attendance -- United States -- Statistics; Education, Higher -- United States
- Problems in United States-Japanese economic relations (Reports 005900), 1972 (Box 263)
  "This article is a slightly revised version of Testimony on United States Foreign Economic Policy Toward Japan to United States Congress. House Committee on Foreign Affairs, Subcommittee on Foreign Economic Policy, November 4, 1971." -- T.p.
  L72-75
  17 leaves + attachments -- 28 cm.
  International economic relations; Ford Foundation. National Affairs
- Language planning and the development and the implementation of language teaching programs (Reports 005901), 1966 (Box 263)
  International Division/Office of the Vice President/Middle East and Africa
  L72-76
  English language -- Study and teaching -- Sudan; French language -- Study and teaching -- Sudan
- Further trimmings for the budget of the Latin America and Caribbean Program (Reports 005902), 1974 (Box 263)
  Memorandum to David Bell dated December 26, 1974.
  7 p. + attachments: tables
  Charity organization -- Latin America; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Finance; Endowments -- Latin America -- Evaluation; Ford Foundation. Latin America and the Caribbean; Ford Foundation
- Report on the outcome of OLAC's response to Mr. Bundy's "Overhang" memorandum of October 8, 1974 (Reports 005903) (Box 263)
  Memo to David Bell dated October 31, 1974.
  8 leaves: principally tables
  OLAC's response to Mr. Bundy's "Overhang" memorandum of October 8, 1974
  Agriculture -- Study and teaching -- Latin America; Agriculture -- Study and teaching -- Caribbean Area; Agricultural assistance -- Latin America; Agricultural assistance -- Caribbean Area; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Finance; Ford Foundation. Latin America and the Caribbean; Ford Foundation
- Proposed request for appropriation of $4.5 million for tie-off grants (Reports 005904), 1974 (Box 263)
  Memo to McGeorge Bundy dated April 30, 1974.
  Tie-off Grants: proposed request for appropriation of $4.5 million ...
  Charity organization -- Developing countries; Endowments -- Developing countries -- Evaluation; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Finance; Ford Foundation. Latin America and the Caribbean; Ford Foundation
- International Division: appropriation for Turnaround Funds (Reports 005905), 1973 (Box 264)
  Appropriation for Turnaround Funds, November 1973 ...
  Charity organization -- Developing countries; Endowments -- Developing countries -- Evaluation; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Finance; Ford Foundation. International Division; Ford Foundation
- Report on trip to Jamaica (Reports 005906), 1968 (Box 264)
  Memo to Hgarry Wilhelm dated Februar 23, 1968.
  Education, Higher -- Jamaica; Social sciences -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- West Indies; Universities and colleges -- Jamaica; Educational assistance -- Jamaica; University of the West Indies
- Discussion notes on Foundation investment in agriculture and rural development (Reports 005907), 1973 (Box 264)
  Memo to Lowell Hardin dated August 10, 1973.
  8 p. + attachments: table
  Foundation investment in agriculture and rural development ...
  Agricultural assistance -- Developing countries; Rural development -- Developing countries; Endowments -- Developing countries -- Evaluation; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Finance; Ford Foundation. International Division; Ford Foundation
- Foundation's agricultural program in Latin America (Reports 005908), 1973 (Box 264)
  12 p.: tables
  Ford Foundation's Agricultural Program in Latin America
  Agricultural assistance -- Latin America; Charity organization -- Latin America; Endowments -- Latin America -- Evaluation; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Finance; Ford Foundation. Latin America and the Caribbean; Ford Foundation
- Reducing Ford Foundation grants for core operating expenses of international centers (Reports 005909), 1973 (Box 264)
  Memo to Lowell Hardin dated July 23, 1973.
  Ford Foundation grants for core operating expenses of international centers
  Agriculture -- Research -- Developing countries; Agricultural assistance -- Developing countries; Charity organization -- Developing countries; Endowments -- Developing countries -- Evaluation; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Finance; Ford Foundation. International Division; Ford Foundation
- International Division budget planning (Reports 005910), 1973 (Box 264)
  Memo to William Carmichael dated May 25, 1973.
  Charity organization -- Developing countries; Social planning -- Developing countries; Economic development -- Developing Countries; Economic assistance -- Developing countries; Population assistance -- Developing countries; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations; Ford Foundation. International Division; Ford Foundation
- Budget tables for trustee discussions (Reports 005911), 1973 (Box 264)
  Memo to Mr. Sutton, Heads, and ID-POICs, dated March 28, 1973.
  8 p.: principally tables
  Trustee discussions ...
  Endowments -- Developing countries; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Finance; Ford Foundation. Board of Trustees; Ford Foundation
- Proposed resource base and regional development assistance, fiscal years 1974 and (Reports 005912), 1973 (Box 264)
  Memo to W. D. Carmichael dated February 8, 1973.
  Resource base and regional development assistance ...
  Agriculture -- Research -- Latin America; Agriculture -- Research -- Caribbean Area; Ford Foundation -- Finance; Ford Foundation. Latin America and the Caribbean
- Preliminary comments on the Federal Budget for FY 1974 (Reports 005913), 1973 (Box 264)
  Memo to McGeorge Bundy dated February 8, 1973.
  6 p. + attachments.
  Federal Budget for FY 1974 ...